Michael Wheeler

Back End Developer

michael.wheeler856@gmail.com

Profile

A software developer with varied experience working in small, cross-functional teams through the full application lifecycle. Projects have covered web and desktop applications, data pipelines and analytics, test automation frameworks and web authentication plugins. All projects have been completed to a high level of coding standards, with excellent test coverage and deployment through CI/CD pipelines.

Experience

Opia Limited, Newcastle upon Tyne

September 2019 - Present

Back End Developer

September 2019 - Present

Working as part of a small back end development team to rebuild the internal systems in an event driven microservices architecture hosted in AWS. Key tasks include designing and building API's and creating automated integrations with suppliers through API's and SFTP.

- PHP, MySQL, VueJS, Vuex.
- Testing: PHPUnit, Prophecy.
- DevOps Tools: Docker, Rancher, Jenkins, Rancher.

MagenTys, an NTT DATA company, London

September 2018 - Present

Senior Application Software Development Consultant

May 2019 - Present

Creation of a test automation framework for a large-scale digital transformation project, utilising REST API's to automate integration tests between Oracle SaaS products, Azure hosted systems and on-site tools.

- Framework: C#, Ninject, Serilog.
- Testing: NUnit, NSubstitute.
- DevOps Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Bamboo, Azure, Artifactory.

Application Software Development Consultant

September 2018 - May 2019

Worked at EE in a team of two, building ETL processes in Python, performing data analysis and displaying results in a dashboard. TDD and DataOps were used to ensure well tested code and fast, scalable data analysis. Attention to detail was required to ensure analysis was accurate.

- Data Pipeline and Dashboarding: Python, Elasticsearch, Grafana, Pandas, Webhooks.
- Testing: unittest.
- DevOps Tools: AWS, Docker, Jenkins.

MagenTys, London

October 2017 - September 2018

Software Development Engineer In Test

May 2018 - September 2018

Continuation of M&S POS transformation, expanding desktop applications and maintenance of trial tills. Included creation of a Java application to broker messages from peripheral devices such as scanners to applications.

• Device Broker Software: Spring Boot Java, JavaPOS, Sock.js, websockets.

Junior Software Development Engineer In Test

October 2017 - April 2018

Project to replace the entire M&S till and back office hardware. Included creation, deployment and maintenance of several new applications as part of a cross-functional, agile team. DevOps best practices were implemented to manage, build and release automation.

- Desktop Applications: Node.js (Electron), C# (WPF, ASP.NET), Java.
- Testing: NUnit, JUnit, Mockito, Mocha, Pester, Jasmine, Spectron, NSubstitute.
- DevOps Tools: Terraform, Ansible, Jenkins, Azure, Nuget, Nexus, Powershell and Bash Scripting.

Qualifications

I have completed the Architecting on AWS course and plan to sit the Associate AWS Certified Solutions Architect exam in the near future.

Education

University of Warwick - Physics MPhys, BSc (Upper Second Class)

Oct 2011 - Jun 2015

- Developed excellent problem solving skills.
- Masters research project: X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy of Modified Semiconductor Surfaces.
- Won a grant of £2700 from the Lord Rootes Memorial Fund to complete a solo 5,000km bike tour across Europe.